Guide to the J. Doane Stott papers, 1748-1999, bulk 1915-1989 RL.11837
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Doane Stott papers
1748-1999
1915-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Stott, J. Doane (Janadus Doane), 1898-1989
RL.11837
4.5 Linear Feet 1500 items
J. Doane Stott was a Methodist minister (N.C. conference) and missionary to Japan. A.B., Trinity College and B.D., Duke University. Chiefly sermons, clippings, and printed material of J. Doane Stott relating to his missionary work in Japan and ministry in North Carolina, as well as his lecture notes reflecting his time spent at Trinity College and Duke University. Papers also include items relating to Mr. Stott's involvement with CROP (Christian Rural Overseas Program), the Greensboro Urban Ministry, as well as the Lion's Club.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, Clippings, Printed Material, Activities and Clubs, and Miscellaneous.
Biographical / Historical
J. Doane Stott was a Methodist minister (N.C. conference) and missionary to Japan. A.B., Trinity College and B.D., Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Doane Stott were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1986 and 1993-1994.
Collection Overview
Chiefly sermons, clippings, and printed material of J. Doane Stott relating to his missionary work in Japan and ministry in North Carolina, as well as his lecture notes reflecting his time spent at Trinity College and Duke University. Papers also include items relating to Mr. Stott's involvement with CROP (Christian Rural Overseas Program), the Greensboro Urban Ministry, as well as the Lion's Club.
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Methodist Church -- North Carolina -- Clergy; Methodist Church -- Missions -- Japan; Missionaries -- Japan; Clergy -- North Carolina; North Carolina -- Religious life and customs; Sermons; Prayers; Stott, J. Doane (Janadus Doane), 1898-1989
- Correspondence, 1942-1980 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  The Correspondence Series, featuring material mainly from friends and churches, contains references for Mr. Stott from various North Carolina politicians and businessmen and church invitations asking him to conduct services.
  - Correspondence, 1942 February 23-1980 July and undated (Box 1)
- Writings and Speeches, 1748-1969
  Although most of the Writings and Speeches Series consists of sermons, class assignments, or debates, there is some printed material included if the items contained handwritten notes. The Brotherhood folder contains sermons and other items relating to race relations, mostly within the context of the Methodist church and its relationship with African Americans. The Sermons and Notes folder include several eulogies and many prayers by Mr. Stott and other ministers, which cover a wide range of topics from the scriptures. Some of these sermons have been transliterated into Japanese.
  - Brotherhood, 1930 March 21-1966 March 5 and undated (Box 1)
  - Class assignments and materials, 1918-1929 and undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Orations and debates, 1916-1920 and undated (Box 1)
  - Revivals, 1945 September 1-1955 April 4 and undated (Box 1)
  - School lectures and talks, 1931 March-1967 February 16 (Box 1)
  - Sermons and notes, 1748-1969; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Sermons and notes, 1970-1989 (Box 2)
  - Stewardship, 1936 June 14-1966 October and undated (Box 2)
- Clippings, 1922-1986
  - Clippings, 1922-1986; 3 folders (Box 2)
- Printed Materials, 1920-1999
  The Printed Material Series includes pamphlets, bulletins, church programs, maps, loose printed pages, as well as journals and books. Most of this material is on either church- or missionary-related topics. There are also a few Duke University alumni publications included.
  - Pamphlets, bulletins, church programs, maps, loose pages, 1920-1999; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - CSA Annual: "In United We Stand--In Cooperation We Achieve" (Box 2)
  - The Christian Century (Box 2)
  - Christianity in the New Japan (Box 2)
  - Decision (Box 2)
  - The Lacour Crusade (Box 2)
  - Man's Spiritual Pilgrimage (Box 2)
  - The Methodist Teacher III-IV (Box 2)
  - The Palmore Messenger (Box 2)
  - Pulpit Preaching (Box 2)
  - Response (Box 2)
  - World Outlook (Box 2)
  - The World's Children in Pictures: Japan (Box 2)
- Activities and Clubs, 1957-1989
  - CROP (Christian Rural Overseas Program) and Greensboro Urban Ministry, 1981 October 11-1989 Fall and undated (Box 3)
  - Lion's Club, 1957 May 13-1975 October 27 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1951-1971 and undated
  The Miscellaneous Series contains many songs and poems, a photograph of a class at Kagawa Central Gospel School in Japan, as well as items relating to Japan and Greensboro, North Carolina.
  - Miscellaneous, 1951-1971 and undated (Box 3)